Guide to the Reynolds Price Papers, 1927-2010 and undated, bulk 1956-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials Series (RESTRICTED), 1968-2003 and undated, (9 boxes)
  - Audio Materials Subseries, 1968-2000 and undated, bulk 1996-2000
    - Audiocassettes, Originals OR1 - OR21 (CLOSED)
      - OR5-14. 1996-2000, Personal essays for National Public Radio's All Things Considered
        - OR5. 1996 Jan. 2, Worship privately rather than in church (TRT unknown)
        - OR6. 1996 Apr. 3 Death penalty (TRT unknown)
        - OR7. 1996 May 8, Death of a friend from AIDS (TRT unknown)
        - OR8. 1996 Oct. 23, Rehabilitation (TRT unknown)
        - OR9. 1996 Nov. 5, Teaching (Recent letter from 1960 student) (TRT unknown)
        - OR10. 1996 Dec. 9, MRI time (TRT unknown)
        - OR11. 1998 Oct. 1, Fortieth anniversary of teaching at Duke (TRT unknown)
        - OR12. 2000 Feb. 3, Teach your children hope (TRT unknown)
        - OR13. 2000 Feb. 28, Depression and suicide (TRT unknown)
        - OR14. 2000 Sept. 21, Teaching writing (TRT unknown)
      - OR15. 1996 Mar. 25, FOL (Friends of the Library) dinner, Meredith College: Bill and Reynolds Price (TRT unknown)
      - OR16. 1996 June 20, Bookworm: Three Gospels (TRT unknown)
      - OR17. 1996, Dickey, James, Sheep Child (TRT unknown)
        See also General Correspondence Subseries, 1997 May 20.
      - OR18. 1996, In Southern Words, Volume II: Family Album (TRT 54:57)
      - OR19. 1997, Lenten Meditation and Music: Duke Chapel (TRT unknown)
        Price reading a short biblical passage.
      - OR20. 1997, Storylines Southeast #12: Clear Pictures, by Reynolds Price (TRT unknown)
      - OR21. Undated, Writers and company: Reynolds Price (TRT unknown)
    - Digital Audio Tapes, Originals OR22-25 (CLOSED)
      Various material recorded by Price. Format for all items is DAT. Arranged chronologically. Total running time (TRT) shown in parentheses if known.
      [RESTRICTED: Materials in this subseries cannot be accessed without permission from Price or his literary executors.]
      - OR22. 1996 Jan. 17, Untitled (TRT unknown) (Box AV1)
      - OR23. 1996 Feb. 23. Untitled (TRT unknown)
      - OR24. 1996 Oct. 8, 1) For Art Silverman, Halloween Show; 2) For Margaret; 3) Commentaries (TRT unknown)
      - OR25. 1998 Sept. 24, Untitled (TRT unknown)
    - Audiotapes, Originals OR26A-B (CLOSED)
      - OR26A and 26B. 1968 Mar. 4, Reading by Reynolds Price and John Cheever at Library of Congress, moderated by James Dickey. Format: 1/4" audiotape, 2 reels. (TRT 74:00) (Box AV1)
    - Audio Materials, Preservation Copies MC2-21, MC26 (Box AV2)
    - Audio Materials, Listening Copies LC2-21, LC26 (Box AV3)
  - Video Materials Subseries, 1981, 1989-2003 and undated
    Interviews, readings, awards ceremonies, and home video. Also includes various events recorded at Duke University. Format is VHS unless otherwise indicated. Arranged chronologically. Viewing copies are available for most items.
    - Original Copies (CLOSED)
      - OR1. 1981 June 3, Dick Cavett Show #4166 (Reynolds Price) (TRT 29:00) (Box AV4)
      - OR2. 1989 Feb. 9-11, A Special Weekend at Duke University, Office of University Development (TRT 18:30)
      - OR3. 1990 May 14, Reynolds Price for Triquarterly (TRT 1:02:57)
      - OR4. 1990 May, Artifacts: Heard, Haxton, Price, (TRT 30:00)
      - OR5. 1990 July 26, North Carolina People: Reynolds Price, (TRT 29:50)
      - OR6. 1991 Aug. 15 or 20, Calvin Klein: Eternity, (TRT 44:53)
      - OR7. 1991 Nov., Writers Reading Reynolds Price (TRT 28:30)
      - OR8. 1991, New Hope Creek, narrated by Reynolds Price (TRT 12:14)
      - OR9. Circa 1991. J.S. [or G.?] H.S., 1951-1991, Fortieth Reunion (TRT 3:36:48)
      - OR10. 1993, The Ninth Van Cliburn International Piano Competition: A Life in Music (TRT 2:00:00)
      - OR11. 1994 Dec. 27, Dateline (with Reynolds Price), (TRT 12:30)
      - OR12. 1994 Sept. 11, Second Sunday Readings, Wilson Library, UNC-CH, Reynolds Price, Reader (TRT 55:10)
      - OR13. 1996 Oct. 31, Reynolds Price: Ghost Stories (TRT unknown)
      - OR14. 1998 May 29, North Carolina Bookwatch: Reynolds Price's 'Roxanna Slade,' (TRT 26:49)
      - OR15. 1999 Apr. 9, North Caroliniana Society Award Banquet, honoring Reynolds Price (TRT 55:00)
      - OR16. 1999 Apr. 9, Reynolds Price: Presentation to North Caroliniana Society (TRT 48:00)
      - OR17. 1999, Tell About the South, Part III: Let Freedom Ring: The History of Modern Southern Literature (1963-present) (TRT 1:09:03) (Box AV5)
      - OR18. 2003 Sept. 17, Threat Matrix: Episode 104, 'In Plane Sight,' Director's Cut (TRT 44:04)
      - OR19. 2003 Sept. 27, Threat Matrix: Episode 103, 'Dr. Germ,' Director's Cut (TRT 43:44)
      - OR20. Undated, Bread on the Waters, Reynolds Price: Teacher, A Documentary by Wil Weldon (TRT 29:00)
      - OR21. Undated, Christmas in Duke Chapel (TRT 55:20)
      - OR22. Undated, The Duke Endowment: 75th Anniversary Symposium Video (TRT 8:30)
      - OR23. Undated, North Carolina People: Reynolds Price (TRT 26:46)
      - OR24. Undated, One Writer's Beginnings: Symphony for Eudora's Eightieth Birthday (TRT 1:00:30
      - OR25. Undated, Reynolds Price Interview (TRT 1:04:15)
      - OR26. Undated, Reynolds Price [at] NYU (TRT 12:31)
      - OR27. Undated, Reynolds Price: A Writer's Inheritance (TRT )
      - OR28. Undated, The Roots of Solitude: The Life and Work of Reynolds Price (TRT 40:00)
      - OR29. Undated, The Writers Workshop: Reynolds Price Benefit Reading (TRT 29:44)
      - OR30. Undated, Untitled (home video) (TRT 14:10)
    - Master Copies
      - Preservation Copies MC1, MC3, MC6, MC12, MC15-17, MC19, MC21 (Box AV6)
      - Preservation Copies MC24-25, MC28-29 (Box AV7)
      - Preservation Copies MC2, MC4-5, MC7-8, MC11, MC14, MC18, MC20, MC22-23, MC26-27, MC30 (Box AV8)
    - Viewing Copies
      - Viewing copies VC1-8, VC11-14, VC16-30 (Box AV9)
- Electronic Formats Series (RESTRICTED), circa 1983-2001 and undated, (141 files on 25 diskettes; 16 files in one compressed file)
  Digital files, mostly unidentified beyond general categories. Mainly correspondence and writings by Price. Also includes text, visual, and audio files created for a Perkins Library exhibit on Price in 2001. Arranged in order in which disks were received and numbered.
  [RESTRICTED: All restrictions applicable to the corresponding series and subseries in print materials also apply to the materials in the Electronic Formats Series. See series notes for Correspondence Series and Writings Series for further details.]
  - Disk 001. Correspondence, circa 1990-1992 and undated, (31 files)
  - Disk 002. Correspondence and writings, circa 1990-1996, (1 file)
  - Disk 003. Writings, including essays, circa 1990-1996, (7 files)
  - Disk 004. Writings, including essays, circa 1990-1996, (11 files)
  - Disk 005. Writings, possibly journals or drafts of A Whole New Life, circa 1992-1994, (2 files)
  - Disk 006. Writings, including notes for proposed works, 1991, (2 files)
  - Disk 007. Writings, including drafts of A Whole New Life, 1992-1994, (3 files)
  - Disk 008. Writings, including drafts of A Whole New Life, 1992-1994, (3 files)
  - Disk 009. Writings, including drafts of Blue Calhoun, circa 1990-1991, (3 files)
  - Disk 010. Writings, including essays and journals, circa 1983, (4 files)
  - Disk 011. Writings, including drafts of Blue Calhoun, circa 1990-1991, (7 files)
  - Disk 012. Writings, including drafts of a screenplay for A Long and Happy Life, undated, (3 files)
  - Disk 013. Writings and correspondence, including drafts of a screenplay for A Long and Happy Life, 1991, (4 files)
  - Disk 014. Writings and correspondence, including drafts of Blue Calhoun, circa 1990-1991, (3 files)
  - Disk 015. Writings, including drafts of A Whole New Life, circa 1992-1994, (1 file)
  - Disk 016. Correspondence and writings, including drafts of poems, circa 1990, (5 files)
  - Disk 017. Correspondence and writings, including drafts of a play, circa 1991, (2 files)
  - Disk 018. Writings, including drafts of a screenplay of The Tongues of Angels, circa 1991, (4 files)
  - Disk 019. Writings, including drafts of stories, undated, (4 files)
  - Disk 020. Writings, including drafts of a play, circa 1991, (5 files)
  - Disk 021. Writings, including drafts of stories, undated, (11 files)
  - Disk 022. Correspondence and writings, including drafts of stories, circa 1992, (12 files)
  - Disk 023. Writings, including drafts of stories, undated, (9 files)
  - Disk 024. Writings, including drafts of poems, 1992, (2 files)
  - Disk 025. Writings, including drafts of Blue Calhoun, undated, (2 files)
  - Compressed file: Reynolds_Price.zip, 2001 Nov., (16 extractable files in 1 compressed file)
    HTML, GIF, and MP3 files created for a Perkins Library exhibit on Reynolds Price as a teacher.
- Oversize Materials (RESTRICTED), (15 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
  RESTRICTED: Most series and subseries have restrictions that apply during Price's lifetime and for twenty years thereafter. For specific restrictions on Oversize Materials, see note for corresponding series and subseries in main body of collection.
  - Correspondence Series, 1956-2002 and undated (RESTRICTED)
    - General Correspondence Subseries, 1956-2000 and undated
      - 1956-1992, (4 folders) (Oversize-box OS1)
      - 1992-2000 and undated, (10 folders) (Oversize-box OS8)
    - Authors' Correspondence Subseries, 1969-2002 and undated
      - Blackburn, William, 1979 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Broughton, T. Alan, 1989
      - Gurganus, Allan, undated
      - Henley, Beth, 1989
      - Humphreys, Josephine, 1984
      - Kizer, Carolyn, 1973
      - Settle, Mary Lee, 1979
      - Steele, Max, 1975
      - Welty, Eudora, 1969-1989, (2 folders)
      - Williams, Jonathan, 1977-1978
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1997, 2002
  - Writings Series, 1935-2003 and undated (RESTRICTED)
    - Writings by Price Subseries, 1954-2003 and undated
      - Student work, 1954 (Oversize-box OS2)
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1961-1990 and undated
      - A Long and Happy Life (1961)
        - Proofs, 1961-1964, (3 folders)
        - Notes and drafts, undated
      - The Names and Faces of Heroes (1963)
        - Proofs, 1963, (2 folders)
      - A Generous Man (1966)
        - Proofs, 1966, (4 folders)
      - Love and Work (1968) (Oversize-box OS3)
        - Proofs, 1968, (2 folders)
      - Permanent Errors (1970)
        - Proofs, 1970, (4 folders)
      - Things Themselves (1972)
        - Proofs, 1972, (4 folders)
      - Presence and Absence (1973)
        - Author's corrected galley proof, 1973
      - The Surface of Earth (1975)
        - Galley proofs for Esquire, 1973
        - Proofs, 1975, (3 folders)
        - Proofs, 1975, (4 folders) (Oversize-box OS4)
      - Early Dark (1977)
        - Proofs, 1977, (3 folders)
      - Lessons Learned (1977)
        - At the Gulf, galley proof, 1977
      - Damon's Epitaph, galley proof, 1978
      - A Palpable God (1978)
        - Plate proof, 1978
        - Proofs, 1978, (3 folders) (Oversize-box OS5)
      - The Source of Light (1981)
        - Proofs, 1981, (4 folders)
        - Plate proof, 1981 (Oversize-box OS8)
      - Reynolds Price on Writing in Southern Review, galley proof, circa 1982 (Oversize-box OS4)
      - Private Contentment (1984)
        - Proof, 1984
      - Kate Vaiden (1986) (Oversize-box OS6)
        - Master proof, 1986
        - Cover proofs, undated (Oversize-box OS8)
      - A Common Room (1987) (Oversize-box OS6)
        - Galley proof, miscellaneous pages, 1987
        - First proof, with Harry Ford's and Price's corrections, 1987 Aug. 27 (Oversize-box OS8)
        - Master proof, miscellaneous pages with Price's corrections, 1987 Aug. 27
        - You Are Needed Now and Always Will Be, galleys for Esquire, 1975 Dec. 29 (Opaperfolder OC:IV:7)
        - You Are Needed Now and Always Will Be, proof (partial), 1976 (Oversize-box OS8)
      - Clear Pictures (1989) (Oversize-box OS6)
        - Proofs and notes on illustrations, 1989, (3 folders)
      - The Only News, galley proof, 1989
      - The Use of Fire (1990)
        - Printer's first proof, 1989
      - The Tongues of Angels (1990)
        - Printer's first proof and master proof, 1990
        - Cover proofs, undated (Oversize-box OS9)
      - Blue Calhoun (1992) (Oversize-box OS6)
        - Proofreader's and master galleys, 1991, (2 folders)
        - Sample covers, undated (Oversize-box OS9)
      - The Collected Stories (fiction, 1993)
        - Sample pages, 1992
        - Jacket proofs, 2003 and undated
      - A Whole New Life (nonfiction, 1994)
        - Jacket proofs, undated
      - The Promise of Rest (novel, 1995)
        - Sample pages (three sets) 1994 Nov. 2-7
        - Jacket proofs and ads, undated
      - The Three Gospels (1996)
        - Cover proofs, undated
      - The Collected Poems (poetry, 1997)
        Jacket proofs, undated
      - Roxanna Slade (novel, 1998)
        - Preliminary jacket copies, 1997 (Oversize-box OS2)
        - Ad, 1998 May 11 (Oversize-box OS9)
        - Sample cover, undated
      - Learning a Trade (nonfiction, 1998)
        - Sample layouts, 1998 Feb. 24-Mar. 31
      - A Singular Family (novels, 1999)
      - A Perfect Friend (2000) (Oversize-box OS2)
        - Jacket proofs, 2000 and undated
      - A Great Circle (novels, 2001) (Oversize-box OS9)
        - Jacket proofs, undated
      - Noble Norfleet (novel, 2002)
        - Jacket proofs, 2002 and undated
      - A Serious Way of Wondering (nonfiction, 2003)
        - Jacket proofs, 2003 Mar. 12
      - Proof of Price: Improving intellectual life at Duke/Fulfilling our half of the deal, Duke Dialogue, 1993 Jan. 15
      - Review of The Illustrated Life of Jesus Through the Centuries and One Jesus, Many Christs, proof, 1998 Sept. 11
      - Proofs of A High Old Time: Reynolds Price Remembers Eudora Welty, 2001 Oct. 17
      - Seeing, Loving, and Behaving Yourself, galley proof for Encounter with comments by Stephen Spender, undated (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Writings by Others Subseries, 1961, 1972, and undated
      - Spender, Stephen (Oversize-box OS1)
        - The Connecting Imagination, 1961 Apr. 1
        - Engaged in Writing galley proof, undated
      - Welty, Eudora
        - The Optimist's Daughter, galley proof, 1972
  - Printed Materials Series, 1937-2000 and undated
    - Serials Subseries, 1950-2000 and undated
      - 1962-1969, (22 folders) (Oversize-box OS10)
      - 1970-1981, (25 folders) (Oversize-box OS11)
      - 1981-1991, (42 folders) (Oversize-box OS12)
      - 1992-2000, (10 folders) (Oversize-box OS13)
      - Stuart Wright items: miscellaneous serials and clippings, 1950-1989 and undated, (7 folders)
    - Clippings Subseries, 1937-1993 and undated
      - Clippings about specific books, arranged chronologically by original date of publication of title, 1962-1977 and undated (Oversize-box OS14)
        - A Long and Happy Life (1962), (2 folders)
        - The Names and Faces of Heroes (1963)
        - A Generous Man (1966)
        - Love and Work (1968)
        - Permanent Errors (1970)
        - Things Themselves (1972)
        - The Surface of Earth (1975)
      - General clippings about and by Price, arranged chronologically, 1937-1993 and undated (Oversize-box OS6 and OS15)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Materials Subseries, 1970-1996 and undated
      - Announcements and programs for appearances by the author, 1976-1990 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Awards and honorary degrees, 1991-1996, (2 folders) (Oversize-box OS8)
      - Map of Mexico and Yucatan trip, circa 1970-1979 (Opaperfolder OC:IV:7)
      - Posters advertising books and lectures, 1982 and 1986
      - Stage plan for Private Contentment, 1985
  - Personal Papers Series, 1939 and undated
    - Blueprints and drawings, 1939 and undated (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Photographic Materials Series, 1951
    - Price's high school graduating class, 1951 May 26 (Oversize-box OS7)
- Accession, 2007 (2007-0009), (18) Boxes
  - Correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
  - Typescripts and drafts
    - Letter to a Godchild
    - A Long and Happy Life (screenplay)
  - Personal documents
  - Correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 2)
  - Typescripts and drafts
    - Letter to a Godchild
    - A Long and Happy Life (screenplay)
    - A Serious Way of Wondering
  - Personal documents
  - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Notes for a novel
  - Typescript of Klonsky and Schwarz by Romulus Linney
  - Personal documents
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Typescript of The Good Priest's Son
  - Correspondence, 2003-2005
  - Typescripts and drafts
    - Letter to a Godchild
    - The Good Priest's Son
  - Personal documents
  - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 6)
  - Typescripts and drafts
    - Letter to a Godchild
    - The Good Priest's Son
  - Personal Documents
  - Typescripts and drafts of The Good Priest's Son (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 8)
  - Personal Documents
  - Photographs, (3 items)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 9)
  - Typescripts and drafts of The Good Priest's Son
  - Personal documents
  - Photographs, (46 items)
  - DVD titled Faces from Hurricane Floyd
  - Typescripts and drafts (Box 10)
    - The Good Priest's Son
    - Marrs, Suzanne. Eudora Welty: a Biography
    - Untitled manuscript
  - Personal papers
  - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 11)
  - Typescript of David Plante's American Ghost
  - Personal files
  - Taxes, 2003
  - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 12)
  - Typescript
    Adaptation of Price's Roxanna Slade by Paul Fleschner
  - Personal documents
  - typescript of The Good Priest's Son (Box 13)
  - Printed books. Some with inscriptions to Price.
    - Smith, R. T. Faith
    - Soliloquy of a Farmer's Wife, the diary of Annie Elliott Perrin
  - Printed Books. Some with inscriptions to Price. (Box 14)
    - Gilbert, Sandra M. Inventions of Farewell
    - Donoghue, Denis. The Practice of Reading
    - Morgan, Robert. Brave Enemies
    - Marrs, Suzanne. Eudora Welty: a Biography
    - Wilson, John (Ed.) The Best Chrisitan Writing 2001
    - Mosse, Ruth. The Wreath Ribbon Quilt
  - Printed Books. Some with inscriptions to Price. (Box 15)
    - Randall, Wallace. Love and Honor
    - Burkey, David F. Higher Ground
    - Malone, Michael. The Last Novel
    - Powell, H. Jefferson. A Community Built on Words
    - Borowsky, Irvin J. (Ed.) Defining New Christian/Jewish Dialogue
    - Cox, Elizabeth. Bargains in the Real World
    - Matthiessen, Peter. Far Tortuga
    - Bly, Robert. The Night Abraham Called to the Stars
  - Printed Books. Some with inscriptions to Price. (Box 16)
    - Tóibín, Colm. The Master
    - Brubach, Holly. Girlfriend: Men, Women, and Drag
    - Carter, Stephen L. The Emperor of Ocean Park
    - Donoghue, Denis. Speaking of Beauty
    - Ruhlman, Michael. Walk on Water
    - Carmichael, Jacqueline Miller. Trumpeting a Fiery Sound
  - Printed Books. Some with inscriptions to Price. (Box 17)
    - McCoy-Thompson, Steve. Weather Boy: A Story of D-Day
    - Willimon, William H. (Ed.). Sermons from Duke Chapel
    - Ward, Evelyn D. The Children of Bladensfield
    - Hauerwas, Stanley. With the Grain of the Universe
  - Printed books (Box 18)
    - Ripert, Eric and Michael Ruhlman. A Return to Cooking
  - Book covers
  - New York Times Book Review, August 14, 2005
  - Degree from the University of North Carolina
  - Typescripts and drafts of miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 19)
  - Full Moon script (Box 19)
  - Better Days script (Box 19)
- Accession (2009-0105), (1 box)
  Addition (2009-0105) (12 items; 0.6 lin. ft.) consists largely of books from Price's writing, teaching, and research, including some text books as well as novels with his notes in the margins. Also included is one folder of miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1972-1994.
  - Reynolds Price miscellaneous folder, 1972-1994 (Box 1)
  - The Surface of Earth, by Reynolds Price
  - The Source of Light, by Reynolds Price
  - Mono Lescaut, by Abbe Prevost
  - Samson Agonistes, by Milton, ed. by F.T. Prince
  - Wuthering Heights, by Emily Bronte
  - David Copperfield, by Charles Dickens
  - The Longman Anthology of Contemporary American Poetry
  - The Golden Hind
  - Seventeenth Century Prose and Poetry
    Student textbook, 1953.
  - Aubrey's Brief Lives
  - The Good News According to John: a translation begun on 14 VII 1991
    Handwritten bound volume.
- Accession (2011-0013), (9 boxes)
  The majority of this addition consists of drafts, revisions, additions, and other materials from writing and publication of Ardent Spirits, Price's 2009 memoir about his time at Oxford University and his early teaching career at Duke. Other writings and drafts in this addition include A Long and Happy Life, Letter to a Godchild, and Clear Pictures.
  The remainder of the addition is sorted into teaching materials, events, correspondence, and miscellaneous material, including photographs, newspaper clippings, and a disassembled scrapbook.
  Like the rest of the collection, this accession is RESTRICTED. Any non-published materials require permission prior to access. Student grades and financial materials are CLOSED.
  - Ardent Spirits (Box 1)
    - A possible adult memoir - first draft
    - Proposal book II
    - Edited copy: J.C.A. pg. 1-693, May 2007, (5 folders)
    - Draft prior to radical revision, 2007 June 7, (4 folders)
    - Proofreading copy, 2007 December 5, (3 folders)
    - Stylistic details and edited copy, 2008 July, (4 folders)
    - First pass, 2008 October 14, (3 folders)
    - First pass copy-Scribner, 2008 October 15, (Folders 1-2 of 3)
    - First pass copy-Scribner, 2008 October 15, (Folder 3 of 3) (Box 2)
    - Author's second pass corrections, 2008 November 17, (3 folders)
    - Copy, 2008, November 17, (3 folders)
    - Draft, 2008 December 16, (2 folders)
    - Copy, 2008 December 16, (3 folders)
    - Punctuation and draft, 2008, (4 folders)
    - Copy, 793 pages, (Folders 1-4 of 6)
    - Copy, 793 pages, (Folders 5-6 of 6) (Box 3)
    - Part One draft, pages 1-223
    - Additions to One
    - Part Two revision, 2006 August 4
    - Part Two revision, 2006 July 29
    - Part Two revision, 2006 November 26, (2 folders)
    - Part Two draft, (3 folders)
    - Part Two revision
    - Drafts
      - Copy-edited manuscript, Cover-Page 622, (4 folders)
      - Pages 1-395, (3 folders)
      - Pages 101-158
      - Pages 224-639, (Folders 1-2 of 3)
      - Pages 224-639, (Folder 3 of 3) (Box 4)
      - Page 2; 343; 421; 490
      - Pages 301-312
      - Pages 308-335
      - Pages 321-343
      - Pages 321-332
      - Loose drafts, pages 396-467
      - Pages 424; 443; 2-165
      - Pages 427-548
      - Loose drafts, pages 427-680, (2 folders)
      - Pages 428-445
      - Pages 447-450
      - Pages 450-458; 324
      - Pages 450-463
      - Pages 457-461
      - Pages 471-503
      - Pages 471-538
      - Pages 474-532
      - Pages 493-521
      - Pages 522-527
      - Pages 601-633
    - Miscellaneous edits, (8 folders)
    - Author biography and pictures
    - Instructions for the copy editor
    - Design layouts and edits
    - Photo captions (original and revised)
    - Production art return book images
    - Chornological notes and letters, 1955-1960
    - Transcribed chronological notes, 1961 July 20-1962 May 11, dated 2006
    - Electronic journal entry printouts, 2005 May-December
    - Events and copies
  - Other works (Box 5)
    - Untitled story: first draft, 1949 August 21
    - Eva-revised, 1949 August 21 (incomplete)
    - Miscellaneous drafts, untitled story
    - One Half of the Deal
    - Letters to a Godchild-mail list
    - Letters to a Godchild drafts, (2 folders)
    - At the Brink-John Beerman
    - About John Beerman, 2009
    - A Long and Happy Life